well everybody goes through the same
status okay here we go let's meditate
[Music]
before you meditate take one good look
behind you out the windows at this
beautiful valley and the mountains
because we're going to use them probably
your karma put them there for this class
[Music]
Donna mountain owns all of those
mountains that's for your students
retreat cottages okay okay here we go
[Music]
I'll it's relaxed no muscle tension in
your eyelids eyelids are two totally
relaxed
hands are relaxed finger to me that
stomach is tight and a little bit
shoulders are back down
Malthus relaxed happy little smile
you're back on your deathbed
call arms and legs are finished you
can't use them anymore they are broken
they are frozen they will never move
again just also feeling cold
breath stop you fought you fought to
breathe you you fought your whole life
to breathing no that's finished last
breath is finished this meat is dead
your eyes closed last turn
and it's dark
the four elements begin to collapse
first the earth element and you feel
like you're here like a diamond mountain
in that place behind the temple it's a
valley there are mountains all around
you and suddenly everything goes crazy
the earth is shaking like an earthquake
terrible noise loud like explosions the
earth is splitting open rocks are
falling mountains are falling and you
run towards the entrance of Diamond
Mountain you are running because you're
afraid the mountains falling earth
cracking open terrible noise like bombs
exploding the earth is splitting open
everywhere mountains are falling you are
running
[Music]
you reach the entrance of Diamond
Mountain and suddenly huge flood of
water coming down from the mountains
like a ocean waves catches you carries
you out towards the highway huge flood
of water like a mountain like mountain
where's and you are carrying on this way
of huge waves like tsunami and you're
drowning you are fighting to stay up the
waves are carrying you out towards the
highway huge ocean moving from the
mountains that are collapsing and you
are fighting to stay up
finally the water leaves you out you can
think the other side of the highway the
water speeds on it drops it leaves you
in the desert alone and then fire the
Sun gets bigger and bigger the heat of
the Sun burning your body the flames of
the Sun surrounding your body covering
your body you are wrapped in flame
you're burning terrible pain terrible
suffering a fire
then a strong wind like a hurricane
pushing away the fire ripping you you
cannot stand up your calling fighting
against the wind the wind is driving
you're pushing it down across the desert
Benna
everything becomes flat again dark
more quiet
the terrible sounds of the earth
breaking the ocean and the Sun and the
wind now everything gets quite more
quiet it's like you're walking across
the lamb
you're looking at the horizon in the
dark and then very quiet none
and it's almost peaceful
and you can see in dawn coming you see
the dark sky changing on the horizon and
little by little like daybreak the sky
is starting to get a little bit white
color like just before the Sun comes up
and you're walking towards this white
color of the sky like before dawn you
are walking towards it slowly
then you are inside the light it's a
white light soft white light around you
you are still walking
then you can see far away some kind of a
mirage there's a like there's water far
away and you're walking across the
desert towards the water it's shimmering
it's moving like an illusion mirages the
subtle element of Earth is dissolving
into the subtle element of water
you keep walking
you're walking towards the Mirage
and then suddenly everything is like fog
or smoke like there's a big fire so you
don't see fire but you are walking
through smoke everything is like fog or
smoke the element of the subtle element
of water is dissolving into the subtle
element of fire you keep walking through
the smoke just gray smoke
then suddenly you can see sparks in the
smoke tiny sparks not big subtle but
bright red sparks like electric sparks
elementa fire subtle is melting into the
subtle element of win just sparks in
smoke you keep walking through the
sparks slowly
suddenly you see a light in the distance
it's like someone's holding a flashlight
or or there's a fire you come closer
through the smoke and the sparks and
finally you come to a light which is
like only as big as a candle flame and
your mind is getting tinier and tinier
your mind is coming smaller and smaller
and the only thing you can see the only
thing you can think of is a candle flame
and the flame is very still it's not
moving just a steady fire flame like a
candle and that's all you can see your
whole world is this flame small flame
and you're walking towards the plane
and then you're walking into the flame
and then you're coming through the flame
and on the other side is that dawn light
soft quiet light before the Sun comes up
the sky is painted white very small very
quiet you are still walking towards this
light
then that light becomes deep red dark
red like the sunset like a very deep red
sunset and you are still moving you are
still walking towards this light the
white light is behind you you are moving
into the red light whole sky whole mind
is red deep red colors mind is getting
smaller and smaller the red is tiny but
you're inside it and then suddenly
everything blinks out blood you're in
very very dark black again the red is
gone the white is gone the mind is very
very small and you are in blackness in
darkness
and then another feeling comes another
vision like crystal like the inside of a
diamond so you feel like you are inside
a diamond the white is gone the red is
gone even the black is gone everything
is like ice crystal you are inside it
stay here for a few minutes everything
is crystal all around you Kristen
nothing else there just you are in the
crystal will stay here for a few minutes
and slowly come back to your breath
three deep breaths
then you can stretch
[Music]